QI CHEN

DATA ENGINEER

EDUCATION

BS of Computer Science, Dean's List

University of Memphis/TN/2011 - 2015

Platform by Per Scholas

Specialized IT Training / NY/ 2019

Furthered understanding of Big Data and Hadoop technologies. Learned how to extract, scrub, and manipulate real-time and warehouse data using SQL & Java.

SKILLS

Java	
Python	
C++	
MySQL	
Hive	
Sqoop	
Oozie	
AWS	
VMWare	
MapReduce	
Hadoop	
Linux	
API	
REST	
Pandas	

REFERENCES

Richard Duchin

CEO & Co-founder / Vurteau

W: 973-618-6444 **E:** rich@vurteau.com

John-Paul Wenger

Technical Support Lead / Dahua Technology

W: 562-704-6533 **C:** 562-646-6667 **E:** jp.wenger@dahuatech.com

C.	646-598-1337	><	qchen125@gmail.com
()	github.com/swordwielder	in	linkedin.com/in/qifchen

PROFILE

Data analytics specialist with experience in both the Advertising and surveillance security, primarily focused in Software Development, Data Modeling, Automation, Big Data, and Data Distribution. With a BS Degree in Computer Science and 5+ years of in experience in Software & Product Development, I'm looking to hone my skills in fast paced environment, pushing the ceilings of innovation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER

Freelance / New York, NY / 2019

- · Created a Discord bot that gives live weather, crypto and stock data through API calls in Python
- · Developed a REST API for returning sports statistics and betting odds.
- · Implemented chenpost.com on an AWS S3 Bucket to allow clients explore and inquire on potential partnerships.

DATA ENGINEER

Vurteau / New York, NY / 2018-2019

- Developed an API to distribute advertising creative data from S3 Bucket, with Cache to optimize server load usage. (Deployed on AWS EC2)
- · Utilized pandas and numpy to perform data analysis and modeling on advertising campaigns performance for new insight.
- Contributed Ideas to Vurteau's business Model that resulted in our initial \$500k funding.
- Provided research on various web technologies and costs that would help optimize the technological procedures. (AWS Media Tailor for ad insertion, S3 for Storage, EC2 for running Server)

PRODUCT ENGINEER & CONTENT MANAGER

Dahua Tech USA Inc. / Irvine, CA / 2015 - 2018

- Updated and maintained Dahuawiki.com to provide better technical support to the customers including adding YouTube tutorials with 7000 daily hits on website tracked through Google Analytics.
- · Hardware testing/support for clients including but not limited to NVRs, DVRs, IP Cameras, and Analog Cameras via Salesforce.

COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR

Computer Science Learning Center, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2014 - 2015

- · Helped students with coursework and checked coding errors
- Taught & Mentored high school students with interests in Computer Science in the field of game development using Ren'Py